## Stefan Lourens



- stefan.lourens@gmail.com
- http://www.linkedin.com/in/stefanlourens
- https://github.com/stefanlourens
- +27 82 854 0448

Other formats: PDF | HTML | Markdown

# **Background**

I've been a Software Engineer since 2002. I'm well versed in all facets of web-development and maintenance, but mainly focused on Server-Side and Systems development using Java.

Recently started doing some Scala and FP development. I completed the Functional Programming Principles in Scala course through Coursera. Opportunities providing further exposure would be ideal.

#### **Technologies used:**

- Java / OOP
- JAX-RS / JSON / REST
- JAXB / XML
- JPA
- Hibernate
- Maven / ANT
- SQL / MySQL
- PHP
- HTML / CSS
- JavaSript / jQuery
- Apache / Tomcat / Jetty / JBoss
- Scala / FP

# **Experience**

### Tag: - http://www.tagworldwide.com

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

• April 2013 - Present

Member of global engineering team, rewriting flagship product.

## Yola - http://www.yola.com

#### Senior Software Engineer / Co-Founder

- December 2010 March 2013 (2 years 4 months) Cape Town
- July 2008 December 2010 (2 years 6 months) San Francisco, CA
- February 2007 July 2008 (1 year 6 months) Cape Town (SynthaSite later renamed to Yola)

Primary Engineer on Sitebuilder server-side (Java), responsible for design and implementation of:

- JSON based APIs, exposing functionality and data to JavaScript UI. (RIA)
- Style Framework, allowing development of styles for use by user's sites.
- Widget Framework, allowing development of widgets for use by user's sites.

- Generating PHP source from Abstraction to produce final website for hosting.
- Database design & sharding.
- Application Level Clustering.
- SOA Integration of various internal and 3rd party services.

Development of Partner Platform and APIs allowing 3rd Party ISP integration.

Development of various in-house tools with web-ui's for use by Support / QA

### Clicks2Customers

#### **Software Engineer**

• March 2006 - February 2007 (1 year)

Design and implementation of various Java / Web-based solutions, ranging from professional services, eg online booking systems, to in-house products and projects eg Affiliate and vertical search engines.

One of the internal products formed the basis that became Yola's SiteBuilder.

### incuBeta

#### **Software Engineer**

• September 2004 - March 2006 (1 year 7 months)

Design and implementation of various Java / Web-based solutions, ranging from professional services, eg online booking systems, to in-house products and projects eg Affiliate and vertical search engines.

### **PSI Systems**

#### **Software Engineer**

• February 2003 - September 2004 (1 year 7 months)

Development of web and desktop applications for various clients (Profesional services)